The Shell isn't just a user interface,
Shell 不只是一个用户界面
it's also a programming language.
它还是一种编程语言
Files containing Shell commands are called Shell scripts.
包含 Shell 命令的文件叫做 Shell 脚本
These can be as simple as one or two commands,
它们可以简单到只是一两行命令
just like you'd write at the Shell prompt.
就像你在 Shell 提示符下所写的
Or they can be long and complex programs
也可以是由很多功能组成的
made of many functions.
长而复杂的程序
But we're not going to look very much into Shell programming
但是在这节课中 我们不会深入探究
in this course.
Shell 编程
However, there's one place that's
而是看一个基本上对使用 Shell 的每个人
very useful to pretty much everyone who uses the Shell,
都非常有用的地方
and that's in customizing the Shell itself.
那就是自定义 Shell
Here's an example, it's really common for Shell users
来看一个例子 Shell 用户通常会
to install programs into a subdirectory of the home
将程序安装到一个叫做 Bin（代表二进制文件）
directory called Bin, which stands for binary.
的主目录的子目录下
But the Shell doesn't come preconfigured to know
但是 Shell 并未预先配置 以知道
that there are any commands there.
其中是否有任何命令
If you have a program installed in bin/magic
如果你有一个程序安装在 bin/magic 下
and you want to run it from the Shell,
且你想从 Shell 运行它
you'd have to type the directory out as well as the command
你得打出目录和命令
name.
名
Now, you can get around that by adding that directory
现在 通过将该目录添加到你的 PATH 路径
to your path variable.
便可做到
But that gets reset every time you start a new Shell.
但是每次你启动一个新 Shell 时 它都会重置
In order to make that change sticky,
为了让此变更成为永久性的
you have to put it into the Shells configuration file.
你需要将其放到 Shell 的配置文件中
Now for historical reasons, there
由于历史原因
are a few different files that the Bash
Bash Shell 能在启动时运行
Shell can run on startup to get its configuration.
几个不同的文件 来获取其配置
On a Mac or on a Windows system with Git Bash,
在带有 Git Bash 的 Mac 或 Windows 系统上
the Shell in every terminal you open will run the commands
你打开的每个终端中的 Shell 将在
in a file called .bash_profile.
名为 .bash_profile 的文件中运行命令
But on a Linux system, .bash_profile is only run
但是在 Linux 系统上 .bash_profile 仅对
for some Shell sessions, specifically log-in Shell
某些 Shell 会话运行 特别是登录 Shell
sessions.
会话
Non-log-in Shells run a file called .bashrc instead.
非登录 Shell 会话则运行一个名为 .bashrc 的文件
Now, this inconsistency can be a problem
如果你想在不同的操作系统上
if you want to use the same Shell configuration
使用相同的 Shell 配置 这种不一致性
on different operating systems.
可能会是个问题
One popular way to get around this is to put a statement
一种常用的解决方法是
into your .bash_profile that says if there is a file called
在你的 .bash_profile 中加入一个语句 说如果有一个
.bash_rc, run that file.
名为 .bash_rc 的文件 则运行它
But if you're only on Mac or Windows,
但是如果你使用的是 Mac 或 Windows
you can just use the .bash_profile without worrying
直接用 .bash_profile 即可 而不用
about that.
担心此问题
Any command you put in this configuration file
你放入此配置文件的任何命令
will be run every time you start the Shell.
都会在你每次启动 Shell 时运行
That includes variable assignments,
这包括变量赋值
like changing dollar sign path.
比如更改 $PATH
It can also include anything you'd
它也可以包含
like to see at the start of your Shell session.
你希望在启动 Shell 会话时看到的任何内容
Maybe you want to see the date and a friendly message.
比如你可能想看到日期和友好消息
No problem, just put the date command there.
没问题 直接在此加上日期命令即可
And maybe something like echo, hey there.
或者加上 echo "Hey there!"
Then when you start a new Shell, the commands you put there get
然后当你启动一个新 Shell 时 你放在其中的命令
run.
就会运行